directblinds.co.uk 2017-01-19

# Our Policy on Privacy - Privacy Policy - Direct Blinds

**PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY**

This policy sets out the basis on which we will treat any personal information that we collect from you and also explains our use of cookies on our site.

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **''Act''** ), the data controller is Swift Direct Blinds Limited, company number 01190828, of 177 Lockwood Road, Huddersfield, HD1 3TG, United Kingdom.

**Personal information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following personal information about you:

  * information that you provide to us in your dealings with us. This includes information provided by you when you create an account with us in order to be able to purchase products displayed on our site, in accordance with our Terms and Conditions of Supply and Use;
  * we may also ask you for information when you request further information from us, or when you report a problem with our site;
  * if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;
  * details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders;
  * details we receive from credit reference and fraud detection agencies;
  * details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data and the resources that you access.

We may hold personal information that you provide to us (such as on a registration form) or that we may obtain from another source (such as our suppliers, marketing organisations or credit reference agencies). This information may include your name, address, date of birth, gender, telephone numbers, email address, bank and credit/debit card information, occupation and employment data and details of how you use our products and general information about the way you pay and manage your account.

**Uses made of the information**

Your personal information may be held and used by us for a number of purposes, including, __ without limitation:

  * processing your orders; administering your account and billing; settling accounts with those who provide related services to us; disclosing your data to bank and debit and credit card companies to validate your debit or credit card details; dealing with requests, enquiries or complaints and other customer care related activities; conducting debt recovery and legal actions;
  * where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes, telling you about our products and special offers which we believe may be of  interest to you; contacting you regarding the products and services of carefully selected third parties;
  * carrying out activities connected with the running of our business such as personnel training, quality control, network monitoring, testing and maintenance of computer and other systems, developing new products and services and in connection with the transfer of any part of our business in respect of which you are a customer; and
  * carrying out any activity or disclosure in connection with a legal, governmental or regulatory requirement on us or in connection with legal proceedings, and for the prevention and detection of crime or fraud and the prosecution of offenders or suspected offenders.

If you are an existing customer, we may also contact you with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

**Disclosure of your personal information**

We may disclose your personal information for processing to our employees, third party consultants, contractors or other service providers who may access your personal information when providing services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information  to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; and
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information  in order to comply with any legal, governmental or regulatory obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions of Supply.

**Your rights in relation to your personal information**

If you would like us to tell you what personal information we hold about you, please write to: The Data Controller, Swift Direct Blinds Limited, 177 Lockwood Road, Huddersfield, HD1 3TG, United Kingdom.

We will require proof of your identity before providing you with details of any personal information we may hold about you. Any request may be subject to an administration fee of £10.00 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.  You can also contact us to correct or update any inaccurate or incomplete information and to advise us of any preferences you may have concerning how you can be contacted for marketing purposes.

**Cookies**

Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with an enjoyable experience when you browse our site, and also enables us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

You can delete existing cookies off your hard drive and choose to block new cookies from our site. You can find out how to do this by visiting <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>. However, should you choose to block cookies then some features on our site might not work as expected.

The tables below list the cookies that we collect and the functions that they perform.

_Kentico_

|  |   
---|---|---  
  
**Cookie name**

| 

**Level**

| 

**Description**  
  
Visitor Status

| 

Visitor

| 

Indicates if the visitor is new or returning. Used for tracking the visitors statistic in Web analytics.  
  
Source

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the channel which the user came from (e.g., email, Facebook, Twitter, etc.).  
  
Campaign

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the web analytics Campaign assigned to the visitor.  
  
Tracked Campaigns

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores all the web analytics Campaigns, which should be tracked within a JavaScript snippet.  
  
UrlReferrer

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the URL referrer from which the user arrives on the website.  
  
Current Contact

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the GUID of the contact related to the current site visitor. Used to track activities on the website.  
  
CMSAB<ABtestname>

| 

Visitor

| 

Used to track conversions for the test and maintain consistent page content for the visitor. Stores the name of the page variant assigned to the visitor, the list of performed conversions and information whether visitor is included in A/B testing specified by an A/B test.  
  
CMSMVT<mvtestname>

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the combination of variants assigned to the visitor by an MVT test. Used to track conversions for the test and maintain consistent page content for the visitor.  
  
CMSNoTestMVT<templateid>

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the currently selected MVT combination for editors in the administration interface.  
  
CMSShoppingCart

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores a reference to the user's active shopping cart.  
  
CMSBodyClass

| 

Visitor

| 

Body element class to provide accessibility standards.  
  
CMSEd<GUID>Current

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the current step of Wizard layout web parts.  
  
ChatLoggedInToken

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores the login state for the Chat application (indicates if the user is in the online state).  
  
ChatSupportLoggedInToken

| 

Visitor

| 

Indicates if the user is logged in to the support chat.  
  
<Window name>_<Group ID>_roomID

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores bindings between groups of chat web parts and chat rooms (for a specific window or tab).  
  
chat_autoinitchat_displayed_<GUID>

| 

Visitor

| 

Remembers if the Automatically initiated chat web part was shown to the user (prevents multiple chat initiation messages).  
  
chat_kick_roomid_<room ID>

| 

Visitor

| 

Indicates that the user was kicked from the specified chat room (and is not allowed to return).  
  
StrandsSBS_*

| 

Visitor

| 

Used by the Strands Recommender solely for its own purposes. The cookies are managed on the Strands side.  
  
CMSStrandsTrackEvent_*

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores persistent HTTP context after a page is reloaded. Used for tracking of shopping cart events.  
  
__openid_selector_*

| 

Visitor

| 

Stores OpenId user identification for authentication purposes.  
  
_Google Analytics_

|  |   
---|---|---  
  
**Cookie Name**

| 

**Expiration Time**

| 

**Description**  
  
_ga

| 

2 years

| 

Used to distinguish users.  
  
_gat

| 

10 minutes

| 

Used to throttle request rate.  
  
_Criteo_

**  
** Direct Blinds use Criteo services to present targeted online advertising campaigns through third party publishers. Criteo services will only collect anonymous data, in order to identify which Direct Blinds products you might be interested in.  
Criteo records, via anonymous cookies, which pages you have browsed on their partners' website.

These cookies keep the information of which pages you have visited, and in Direct Blinds case, which products you may viewed and purchased. This data is anonymous and exclusively meant for our statistics. It is not possible Criteo to identify you the visitor. The advertisements do not combine information about you from multiple sources. Criteo do not take user information from a retailer that they may have stored about you. Criteo do not share any data with any site that displays their advertising. If you would like to learn more about Criteo information or, on how to opt out, then please visit **http://www.criteo.com/privacy-policy/**

_AWIN_  
  
---  
  
**1\. Tracking cookies set directly by Affiliate Window:**  
  
**Function**

| 

**Cookie 'name' or id (to facilitate any subsequent conversations about a specific cookie)**

| 

**Cookie Purpose (description)**

| 

**What data does the cookie hold?**

| 

**What is the Cookie expiry date?**  
  
|  |  |  |   
  
Tracking

| 

The cookie name will be different for each advertiser, but will be the letters 'aw' followed by an id to represent the advertiser

| 

Set when you click on one of our links and used to let the advertiser and Direct Blinds know the website from which you came.

| 

* Set when you click on one of our links and used to let the advertiser and Direct Blinds know the website from which you came.                                                                                                        * An id for the referring website                                                                                                    * An id for the ad on which you clicked                                                                           * An id for the group of ads to which the ad belongs                                                           * The time you clicked                                                                                                                * Any reference the referring site adds to the click                                               * An id for the type of ad                                                                                                           * An id for the product

| 

This varies depending on the advertiser and the referring website, but typically will be 30 days  
  
Tracking

| 

AWSESS

| 

Set when you see an ad and used to help us make sure we don't keep showing you the same ad.

| 

* An id for the ad you've seen

| 

When you close your browser  
  
Targeting

| 

The cookie name will be different for each advertiser, but will be the letters ' _awpv_ ' followed by an id to represent the advertiser

| 

Set when you see an ad and used to let the advertiser and Direct Blinds know where you were when you saw it.

| 

* An id for the website that showed the ad                                             * The time you saw the ad

| 

This varies depending on the advertiser, but typically will be 24 hours  
  
Tracking

| 

AW  
 (flash cookie)

| 

Set when you click on one of our links and used to let the advertiser and Direct Blinds know the website from which you came.

| 

* An id for the advertiser site you visited                                                  * An id for the referring website                                                                  * An id for the ad on which you clicked                                                      * An id for the group of ads to which the ad belongs                              * The time at which you clicked                                                                  * Any reference the referring site adds to the click                               * An id for the type of ad                                                                                             * An id for the product

| 

This varies depending on the advertiser and the referring website, but typically will be 30 days  
  
_AWIN_  
  
---  
  
**2\. Tracking cookies set for AWin by advertisers on the advertiser's domain:**  
  
**Function**

| 

**Cookie 'name' or id (to facilitate any subsequent conversations about a specific cookie)**

| 

**Cookie Purpose (description)**

| 

**What data does the cookie hold?**

| 

**What is the Cookie expiry date?**  
  
Tracking

| 

_aw_m_1001 The cookie name will be different for each advertiser, but will be the characters '_aw_m_' followed by an id to represent the advertiser

| 

Set when you click on one of our links and used to let the advertiser and us know the website from which you came.

| 

* An id for the referring website                                                                 * An id for the ad on which you clicked                                                      * An id for the group of ads to which the ad   
belongs                                                                                                                 * The time at which you clicked                                                                   * Any reference the referring site adds to the click                                * An id for the type of ad                                                                               * An id for the product

| 

This varies depending on the   
advertiser and the referring   
website, but typically will be 30   
days  
  
_VE Retargeting_

**Essential cookies:   **These cookies are necessary for Direct Blinds’ website to run properly and efficiently. They remember the information you fill out in forms (Log in, Product Search, etc.) as you navigate through different pages. They allow Direct Blinds to keep your chosen products in a basket, until you are ready for checkout. Without these cookies Direct Blinds could not show search results and previous pages.

**Persistent cookies:** These cookies are saved for a longer periods of time.  These cookies will not be deleted when a browser is closed. These cookies are generally used for advertising. This helps Direct Blinds to know what your product preferences are, to which Direct Blinds can make your future browsing easier to navigate, tailored to your needs, wants and preferences.
